Carlos Andres Santacruz Z.

Software Developer

I'm a systems engineer, and specialist in Gerencia de Proyectos en Construcción de software, with more than 7 years of experience in software development, I have the ability and expertise for to plan, analyze, design, and implement information software; I have knowledge in various development technologies (JAVA, Angular+2, NodeJS, Spring Framework, NestJS, Typescript), database (mysql, postgresql, oracle, mongodb), cloud(AWS, Azure) and software processes (scrum, psp). I characterize myself as a responsible person with a lot of professionalism.

JAVA	Javascript	Kotlin	Spring	NestJS	NodeJS	SQL	NoSQL	Angular	CI/CD	AWS
Azure	Scrum	GIT	Microservicios	Docker	Apache					

Experience

★ Hublance, Senior Backend Developer (Oct 2020 – current)

Proyecto Refinancing debt: Microservices were built in JAVA, Kotlin, and NestJS, for the client's debt refinancing processes. Kafka was used for events and queues, cache memory was managed with Redis, and unit, and integration tests were carried out with Junit, Mockito, and Jest. For data access, I work with JPA and TypeORM. I work with 2 databases, PostgreSQL and MongoDB. Third-party services were also consumed with Feing and Axios. Some AWS functionalities such as S3, CloudWatch, Cognito, and Lambdas are used. Functionalities were also created with reactive programming. Git was used to versioning the projects in Bitbucket. Jenkis is used for continuous integration and pipeline processes. Work was done with docker to build the services and APIs necessary to carry out tests. SonarQube is used for static code and coverage validation. Work under agile methodologies with Scrum. Also, I created resources and I did some updates in AWS from Terraform

<u>Project Shared Services:</u> In charge of services, models, consumption of built services, and unit tests, using technologies and tools such as: GO, Kotlin, APIConnect, AWS, Terraform, Jaeger, Jira, Confluence, MySQL, and Swagger. Repository management (Git), REDIS cache data management, continuous integration tools, and Scrum methodology.

<u>Project Credi-pyme:</u> Responsible for creating models, services, unit tests, and new functionalities in the backend making use of technologies and tools such as Microservices, JAVA, Spring, Camel, Azure, AWS, Terraform, GIT, Hibernate, JUnit, Mockito, Feign, NestJS, Typescript, Jest, GraphQL, Kafka, Docker, Redis, and Scrum. Reactor was used for Java with mono and flush.

★ Planupsoft, Senior Full-stack Developer (Jan 2020 – Oct 2020)

In charge of building the architecture of the client application with the Angular Framework version 8. Creation of models and services in the API - Rest with .Net Core technologies. Management of tools such as Azure DevOPS, IIS server, application deployment (Client, Api - Rest), branch and repository management (Git), deployment through pipelines, and database management (MS SQL SERVER).

★ Universidad Mariana Sistemas y desarrollo, Senior Back-end Java Developer (jan 2020 - aug 2020)

In charge of building the architecture of an API - REST application with technologies (JAVA, Spring boot, hibernate, JWT, reactive programming) as well as supervising the creation of the client application based on the framework (Angular 8) and the modeling of the database for the solution of software for the management of consultancies and courses that will be offered by the university to other companies.

Mail

casz21@hotmail.com

Address

Calle 14 No 16 - 30 Pasto, Colombia

Phone

+57 318 3234711

Age 29

Birth 21-03-1993

Nationality Colombiano

Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.c om/in/andres-santacr uz-030723175/

Aptitudes

Trabajo en equipo Resolución de problemas Liderazgo Dominio de lenguajes de programación

Languages Español – Inglés (intermedio)

Carlos Andres Santacruz Z.

Software Developer

★ Universidad Nariño, Centro de desarrollo e investigación, Desarrollador Full-stack (Angular, Node), (sep 2018 - dec 2019)

I worked with technologies such as Angular 6, Node, Jasper Reports and PostgreSQL, the tasks in which I performed were the migration of the financial part of the university that is developed in .NET to the new technologies mentioned above, taking and analysis of requirements with those involved, database modeling, creation of services (Back-end), design of visual components (Front-end), deployment and configuration of the client application.

★ Proinsalud S.A, Developer Full-stack (may 2017 – sep 2018)

The architecture has structured an application of a new platform that replaced the one that was used previously in this company, an application API - Rest was created, a simple application for the management of the shifts of the waiting rooms, and a small application for Android devices. The technologies used for this development were JAVA, Spring Framework, Primefaces, Javascript, Angular 4, Web Service (API - Rest), Postgres SQL, Node, .NET, and Android.

★ Qualisys - Software de gestión empresarial, Developer Java (jan 2017 - may 2017)

The activities that were developed were to analyze requirements, design the solution, present the proposal, and proceed to development. The tools and languages used to fulfill the functionalities were: Java, Mysgl, Php, Javascript, native Android, SQLite, Java web services, and HeidiSQL.

★ Sistemas y Aplicaciones en línea SAP, Developer Full-stack (oct 2014 - dec 2016)

The functions that were carried out were database design, creation of reports in Jasper reports, creation of entities, "dao" and "services" classes, controller or component, and view. The development of an application for an Android device was also carried out. The technologies used are JAVA, Spring framework, Hibernate, Primefaces, Android, Jasper Reports, Spring STS, Oracle, and SVN repository.

Carlos Andres Santacruz Z.

Software Developer

Education

Especialización en Gerencia de Proyectos en Construcción de Software

Universidad Mariana Pasto , Colombia 2018

Ingeniero de Sistemas

Universidad Mariana Pasto, Colombia 2016

Diplomado en Arquitectura de Software

Universidad Mariana Pasto, Colombia 2012

Técnico Laboral en Multimedia y Manejo de Sistemas Operativos

Universidad Autónoma de Bucaramanga Pasto, Colombia 2009

Bachiller Técnico Comercial con Énfasis en Informática Empresarial

Institución Educativa Municipal INEM Pasto, Colombia 2009

Certificates and courses

- ★ Scrum Fundamentals Certified
- ★ Scrum Study
- ★ Personal Software Process Fundamentals
- ★ Software Engineering Institute
- ★ Diplomado en Arquitectura de Software
- ★ Universidad Mariana
- **★** Udemy
 - Spring Framework 5
 - Angular Framework 8
 - React Framework
 - o Microservicios con Spring Boot y Spring Cloud Netflix Eureka
 - Node JS
 - NestJS Zero to Hero Modern TypeScript Back-end Development
 - o Functional & Reactive Programming in Java

CARLOS ANDRES SANTACRUZ ZAMBRANO C.C. 1085303462